Daenerys: When I was a child,
丹妮莉丝：我小时候，
my brother would tell me
a bedtime story...
我哥哥会告诉我的
睡前故事……
About the man
who murdered our father.
关于这个男人
他谋杀了我们的父亲。
Who stabbed him in the back
and cut his throat.
谁在背后捅了他一刀
割断他的喉咙。
Who sat down on the iron throne
and watched
谁坐上了铁王座
,看着
as his blood poured onto the floor.
他的血倒在地板上。
He told me other stories as well.
他还给我讲了其他的故事。
About all the things
we would do to that man...
关于所有的事情
我们会对那个人做什么…
Once we took back the seven kingdoms
and had him in our grasp.
一旦我们夺回七大王国
把他抓在我们手里。
Your sister pledged
to send her army north.
你妹妹保证
让她的军队北上
She did.
她做到了。
I don't see an army.
我没看到军队。
I see one man, with one hand.
我看到一个人，用一只手。
It appears your sister lied to me.
看来你妹妹骗了我。
She lied to me as well.
她也骗了我。
She never had any intention
of sending her army north.
她从来没有任何意图
派她的军队北上。
She has euron greyjoy's fleet
and 20,000 fresh troops.
她有攸伦·葛雷乔伊的舰队
还有2万名新兵。
The golden company from essos,
bought and paid for.
来自埃索斯的黄金公司，
花钱买的。
Even if we defeat the dead,
即使我们打败了亡灵
she'll have more than enough
to destroy the survivors.
她会有足够的
摧毁幸存者。
I promised to fight for the living.
I intend to keep that promise.
我答应过要为生者而战。
我打算信守诺言。
- Your grace, I know my brother...
- Like you knew your sister?
-陛下，我了解我哥哥…
-就像你认识你妹妹一样？
He came here alone, knowing full well
how he'd be received.
他独自来到这里，心里很清楚
他会受到怎样的接待。
Why would he do that
if he weren't telling the truth?
他为什么要这么做
如果他说的不是实话？
Perhaps he trusts his little brother
to defend him,
也许他信任他的弟弟
为了保护他，
right up to the moment
he slits my throat.
直到现在
他割断了我的喉咙。
Sansa: You're right.
We can't trust him.
珊莎：你说得对。
我们不能相信他。
He attacked my father in the streets.
他在街上袭击了我父亲。
He tried to destroy my house and
my family, the same as he did yours.
他想毁了我的房子
我的家人，就像他对你的家人一样。
Jaime: Do you want me to apologize?
詹姆：你想让我道歉吗？
I won't.
我不会的。
We were at war.
我们当时处于战争状态。
Everything I did,
I did for my house and my family.
我所做的一切，
我是为了我的房子和我的家人。
I'd do it all again.
我愿意再来一次。
The things we do for love.
我们为爱所做的一切。
Daenerys: So why have you abandoned
your house and family now?
丹妮莉丝：那你为什么要放弃
你现在的房子和家人？
Jaime: Because this goes
beyond onalty.
杰米：因为这个
onalty之外。
This is about survival.
这关乎生存。
Brienne: You don't know me well,
your grace.
布蕾妮：你不太了解我，
你的恩典。
But I know ser Jaime.
但我了解詹姆爵士。
He is a man of honor.
他是一个正直的人。
I was his captor once.
我曾经是他的俘虏。
But when we were both taken prisoner
and the men holding us
但当我们都被俘虏的时候
还有抓着我们的人
tried to force themselves on me,
ser Jaime defended me.
试图强迫我
詹姆爵士为我辩护。
And lost his hand because of it.
还因此失去了一只手。
Without him, my lady,
you would not be alive.
没有他，夫人，
你就不会活着了。
He armed me, armored me,
他给我武装，给我盔甲，
and sent me to find you
and bring you home
让我来找你
带你回家
because he'd sworn an oath
to your mother.
因为他发过誓
敬你母亲。
You vouch for him?
你为他担保？
Brienne: I do.
布蕾妮：是的。
You would fight beside him?
你愿意和他并肩作战？
I would.
我会的。
I trust you with my life.
我把生命托付给你。
If you trust him with yours,
we should let him stay.
如果你把你的托付给他
我们应该让他留下。
What does the warden of the north
say about it?
北境守护的职责是什么
说说看？
We need every man we can get.
我们需要所有能找到的人。
Very well.
很好。
Thank you, your grace.
谢谢您，陛下。
Either you knew Cersei was lying
and let me believe othennise,
要么你知道瑟曦在撒谎
让我相信他，
or you didn't know at all.
或者你根本不知道。
Which makes you
either a traitor or a fool.
这让你
不是叛徒就是傻瓜。
- I was a fool.
- Not for the first time.
-我是个傻瓜。
-不是第一次了。
Cersei still sits on the throne.
瑟曦依然坐在王位上。
If you can't help me take it back,
I'll find another hand who can.
如果你不能帮我收回，
我去找另一个会的人。
I suspect one of you will be
wearing this before it's all over.
我猜你们中会有一个
在一切结束前穿上这个。
Man: Coal's coming through.
男：煤运过来了。
Don't you have something better to do?
你没别的事可做吗？
You make my weapon yet?
你给我做武器了吗？
Just as soon as I'm done
making a few thousand of these.
等我弄完就走
做几千个这样的东西。
You should make mine first.
你应该先做我的。
And make sure it's stronger than this.
确保它比这个更坚固。
It's strong enough.
它足够坚固。
It's going to be safer
down in the crypt, you know.
这样会更安全
在地下室，你知道的。
Are you going to be
down in the crypt?
你会吗
在地下室？
- No, but...
- But you're a fighter.
-不，但是…
-但你是个斗士。
I've done my share.
我已经尽力了。
You've fought them?
你和他们打过仗？
I did. Some of them.
我做到了。其中一些。
How many?
有多少?
A few.
几。
That was enough.
这就够了。
What are they like?
他们是什么样的人？
Bad.
坏的。
Really bad.
非常糟糕。
"Really bad"?
“非常糟糕”?
Even a Smith's apprentice
can do better than "really bad."
甚至是铁匠的学徒
可以做得比“非常糟糕”更好。
What do they look like?
What do they smell like?
它们长什么样子？
它们闻起来像什么？
How do they move?
How hard are they to kill?
它们是如何移动的？
杀死它们有多难？
Look, I know you want to fight.
听着，我知道你想吵架。
And I know you're not scared
of rapers or murderers or...
我知道你并不害怕
强奸犯，杀人犯或者…
This is different. This is...
这是不同的。这是……
This is death.
这就是死亡。
You want to know what they're like?
Death. That's what they're like.
你想知道他们是什么样的人吗？
死亡。他们就是这样的人。
I know death.
我了解死亡。
He's got many faces.
他有很多脸。
I look foward to seeing this one.
我很期待看到这个。
- My weapon?
- I'll get right on it.
-我的武器？
-我马上去办。
I'm sorry for what I did to you.
我为我对你做的事感到抱歉。
You weren't sorry then.
那时你并不感到抱歉。
You were protecting your family.
你是在保护你的家人。
I'm not that person anymore.
我不再是那个人了。
You still would be, if you hadn't
pushed me out of that window.
如果你不这么做，你还是会的
把我推出窗外。
And I would still be Brandon stark.
我还是布兰登·斯塔克。
- You're not?
- No.
-你没有？
——没有。
I'm something else now.
我现在不一样了。
You're not angry at me.
你不是在生我的气。
I'm not angry at anyone.
我不生任何人的气。
Why didn't you tell them?
你为什么不告诉他们？
You won't be able to help us
in this fight
你帮不了我们的
在这场战斗中
if I let them murder you first.
如果我让他们先杀了你
What about aftennards?
那日历呢？
How do you know
there is an aftennards?
你怎么知道
有一个下午？
Soldier 1: Next up.
士兵1：下一个。
Soldier 2: Put a marker in the ground!
士兵2：在地上放个标记！
Bring it up to the wall!
把它带到墙上去！
Soldier 3:
Up onto the wall. All right.
士兵3:
在墙上。好吧。
Soldier 4: All right.
Soldier 3: All right.
士兵4：好吧。
士兵3：好吧。
Tyrion: Well, here we are.
提利昂：好吧，我们到了。
Yes, here we are.
是的，我们到了。
Together again.
再次在一起。
And the masses rejoice.
群众欢欣鼓舞。
How do they feel
about their new queen?
他们感觉如何？
关于他们的新女王？
She's your new queen too.
她也是你的新女王。
They remember what happened
他们记得发生了什么
the last time targaryens
brought dragons north.
坦格利安家族的最后一次
把龙带到北方。
They'll come around
once they see Daenerys is different.
他们会回来的
一旦他们看到丹妮莉丝变了
And she is? Different?
她是谁？不同吗?
Tyrion: She is.
提利昂：是的。
- You're sure about her?
- I am.
-你确定吗？
-是的。
She didn't seem sure about you.
她似乎对你不太确定。
It's hard to blame her.
这很难怪她。
I made a mistake
common to clever people.
我犯了一个错误
聪明人的通病。
- I underestimated my opponents.
- Hmm.
-我低估了对手。
——嗯。
Cersei told me the pregnancy
had changed her.
瑟曦告诉我怀孕的事
改变了她。
A chance for you both to start again.
给你们两个重新开始的机会。
And I believed her.
我相信了她。
Was she lying about the baby too?
孩子的事她也撒谎了吗？
No, that part is real.
不，那部分是真的。
She's always been good
at using the truth to tell lies.
她一直都很好
善于用真相来说谎。
I wouldn't be too hard on yourself.
我不会对你太苛刻。
She's fooled me more than anybody.
她比任何人都骗过我。
What?
怎么啦？
She never fooled you.
她从没骗过你。
You always knew
exactly what she was,
你总是知道
她就是这样的人
and you loved her anyway.
但你还是爱她。
We're going to die at winterfell.
我们会死在临冬城。
Not the death I would've chosen.
我不会选择这样的死法
I always pictured myself
dying in my own bed,
我总是想象自己
死在自己的床上，
the age of 80,
80岁的时候，
with a belly full of wine and
肚里满满都是酒
- a girl's mouth around my cock.
- A girl's mouth around your cock.
-一个女孩的嘴在我的鸡巴上。
-一个女孩的嘴在你的鸡巴上。
At least Cersei
won't get to murder me.
至少瑟曦
不会杀了我的。
I'm sure I'll feel some satisfaction
denying her that pleasure
我相信我会感到满意的
拒绝她的快乐
while I'm being ripped apart
by dead men.
而我却被撕成碎片
死的人。
Maybe after I'm dead...
也许等我死后……
I'll march down to king's landing
and rip her apart.
我要去君临
然后把她撕碎。
Man: You will see
the army of the dead.
男：你会看到的
死亡之军。
Podrick: Good.
Podrick:很好。
Yes, aim.
是的,目标。
Don't rush.
不要着急,
Come fon/vard.
丰/ vard来。
- Come on.
- Ser Jaime.
-别这样。
-詹姆爵士。
Lady brienne.
夫人一起。
He's come a long way.
他走了很长一段路。
- He's all right.
- Podrick: One more time. Come on.
-他没事。
再来一次。来吧。
- Still has a lot to learn.
- I'm sure you'll teach him.
-还有很多要学的。
-我相信你会教他的。
Podrick: Better, better.
波德瑞克：好了，好了。
I've been told you're commanding
the left flank.
我听说你是指挥官
左翼。
I am.
我是。
It's, uh... it's good ground.
这是,呃…这块地很好。
It is.
它是。
The rise, it should give us
some advantage.
上升，它应该给我们
一些优势。
If we can keep a tight formation,
we might be able to beat them back.
如果我们能保持紧密队形，
我们也许能打退他们。
Yes, I think you're right.
是的，我认为你是对的。
- What are you doing?
- What?
-你在干什么？
——什么?
- I think you know.
- I truly don't.
-我想你知道。
-我真的不知道。
We have never had a conversation
last this long
我们从来没有说过话
持续这么久
without you insulting me. Not once.
不要你侮辱我。一次也没有。
You want me to insult you?
你想让我侮辱你？
- No!
- Good.
——不!
——好。
I came to winterfell because...
我来临冬城是因为……
I'm not the fighter I used to be.
我不再是以前的那个斗士了。
But I'd be honored to serve under
your command, if you'll have me.
但我很荣幸能在
你的命令，如果你愿意的话。
I better get back.
我得回去了。
Jorah: Forgive me, khaleesi.
乔拉：原谅我，卡丽熙。
Have you done something to offend me?
你做了什么冒犯我的事吗？
Many things.
很多东西。
Long ago and long forgiven.
很久以前，早已原谅。
But you did forgive,
但你原谅了我，
despite my failures.
尽管我失败了。
When I heard you'd named Tyrion
your hand,
当我听说你叫提利昂
你的手,
it broke my heart.
我的心都碎了。
When I named him hand, I didn't
know if I'd ever see you again.
当我叫他手的时候，我没有
我不知道还能不能再见到你
You made the right choice.
你做了正确的选择。
I wasn't under the impression
you liked him very much.
我没有这个印象
你很喜欢他。
I didn't.
我没有。
His mouth hardly stopped moving
between volantis and meereen.
他的嘴几乎不停地动着
在瓦兰提斯和弥琳之间。
It was all I could do
not to throw him in the sea.
这是我所能做的
而不是把他扔进海里。
But the mind behind all those words...
但这些话背后的思想……
He's made mistakes.
他犯了错误。
Serious mistakes.
严重的错误。
As have we all.
我们都是这样。
He owns his
他拥有他的
and learns from them.
并从中学习。
You're advising me to forgive
the man who stole your position?
你建议我去原谅
那个抢走你职位的人？
I am.
我是。
And one other suggestion,
if you'll allow me.
另一个建议是，
如果你允许的话。
Royce: The moment we can get the last
infantryman out onto the field,
罗伊斯：等我们拿到最后一个的时候
步兵来到战场上，
we should shut the gates.
我们应该关上大门。
Sansa: Keep them open
for as long as you can.
珊莎：把它们打开
能待多久就多久。
There are still people coming in
from the countryside.
还有人进来
来自农村。
Lady sansa, I was hoping
we could speak alone.
珊莎小姐，我希望
我们可以单独谈谈。
I thought you and iwere
on the verge of agreement before.
我以为你和我
就在达成协议的边缘。
About ser Jaime.
关于詹姆爵士。
Brienne has been onal to me, always.
布蕾妮一直对我很好。
I trust her more than anyone.
我比任何人都信任她。
I wish I could have
that kind of faith in my advisors.
我希望我可以
对我的顾问这么有信心。
Tyrion is a good man.
提利昂是个好人。
He was never anything but decent
towards me.
他是个正派的人
向我跑来。
I didn't ask him to be my hand
simply because he was good.
我没有让他做我的帮手
只是因为他很优秀。
I asked him to be my hand
because he was good, and intelligent
我请他做我的手
因为他很好，很聪明
and ruthless when he had to be.
必要的时候也很无情。
He never should have trusted Cersei.
他不该相信瑟曦。
You never should have either.
你也不应该这么做。
I thought he knew his sister.
我以为他认识他妹妹。
Families are complicated.
家庭是复杂的。
Ours certainly have been.
我们的当然是。
Sansa: A sad thing to have in common.
珊莎：真是可悲的共同点。
We have other things in common.
我们还有其他共同点。
We've both known what it means
to lead people
我们都知道这意味着什么
去领导人们
who aren't inclined
to accept a woman's rule.
谁不愿意
接受女人的统治。
And we've both done a damn good job
of it, from what I can tell.
我们俩都做得很好
据我所知，这是一件好事。
And yet, I can't help but feel
we're at odds with one another.
然而，我还是忍不住觉得
我们彼此意见不合。
Why is that?
为什么呢？
Your brother.
你的哥哥。
He loves you, you know that.
他爱你，你知道的。
That bothers you?
这让你很困扰？
Men do stupid things for women.
男人会为女人做傻事。
They're easily manipulated.
他们很容易被操纵。
All my life, I've known one goal:
我一生都知道一个目标：
The iron throne.
铁王座。
Taking it back from the people
who destroyed my family,
从人民手中夺回来
他毁了我的家庭
and almost destroyed yours.
还差点毁了你的。
My war was against them.
我的战争是针对他们的。
Until I met Jon.
直到我遇到了乔恩。
Now I'm here, half a world away,
现在我在这里，半个地球之外，
fighting Jon's war alongside him.
和琼恩并肩作战
Tell me, who manipulated whom?
告诉我，是谁操纵了谁？
I should have thanked you
the moment you arrived.
我应该感谢你的
在你到达的那一刻。
That was a mistake.
这是一个错误。
I'm here because
I love your brother...
我来这里是因为
我爱你哥哥……
And I trust him...
我相信他……
And I know he's true to his word.
我知道他是信守诺言的。
He's only the second man in my life
I can say that about.
他只是我生命中的第二个男人
我可以这么说。
Who was the first?
谁是第一个？
Someone taller.
高的人。
And what happens aftennards?
接下来会发生什么呢？
We defeat the dead,
we destroy Cersei.
我们打败了死者，
我们杀了瑟曦。
What happens then?
然后会发生什么？
I take the iron throne.
我坐上铁王座。
What about the north?
那北方呢？
It was taken from us,
and we took it back.
它从我们这里被夺走了
我们把它拿回来了。
And we said we'd never bow
to anyone else again.
我们说过我们永远不会屈服
再给别人。
What about the north?
那北方呢？
Wolkan: Apologies, my lady.
Your grace...
Wolkan：对不起，夫人。
你的恩典……
What is it?
这是什么？
Theon: My queen.
席恩：我的女王。
Your sister?
你的妹妹吗?
She only has a few ships,
and she couldn't sail them here.
她只有几艘船
她不能把他们带到这里来。
So she's sailing
to the iron islands instead,
她在航行
去了铁群岛
to take them back in your name.
以你的名义夺回他们。
But why aren't you with her?
但你为什么没和她在一起？
I want to fight for winterfell,
lady sansa...
我想为临冬城而战
珊莎夫人……
If you'll have me.
如果你愿意的话。
My lord, we're not soldiers.
大人，我们不是士兵。
You are now.
你现在是。
Look, I made it through
most of my years
瞧，我挺过来了
我的大部分岁月
without ever getting near a fight,
没有接近过一场战斗
but then I survived
the battle of the bastards.
但后来我活了下来
私生子之战。
Right outside these walls.
就在墙外。
If I can live through that,
you can live through this.
如果我能挺过去，
你能挺过去的。
They'll outfit you with weapons
at the forge.
他们会给你装备武器
在铁匠铺。
Right that way.
就在那边。
Thank you.
谢谢你！
Gilly: When the time comes,
you'll be down in the crypts.
吉莉：到时候，
你会被关在地下室。
They're the safest place to be.
那里是最安全的地方。
Through that archway
right over there.
穿过那个拱门
就在那里。
Thank you.
谢谢你！
Woman 1: Hey, hey, who's next, lads?
女1：嘿，嘿，下一个是谁，伙计们？
Woman 2: Thank you, sir.
女士2：谢谢你，先生。
Teela: Which way should I go?
缇拉：我该走哪条路？
Which way do you want to go?
你想走哪条路？
All the children will be going below
when the time comes.
所有的孩子都会下到下面去
当时机成熟时。
But both me brothers were soldiers.
但我的兄弟俩都是士兵。
I want to fight too.
我也想打架。
That's good to hear.
很高兴听到这个消息。
I'm going to be in the crypt
with my son,
我要去地下室了
我的儿子，
and I'd feel a lot better
with you down there to protect us.
我就会感觉好多了
有你在下面保护我们。
I'm sure a lot of people would.
我相信很多人都会的。
All right.
I'll defend the crypt, then.
好吧。
那我来守卫地穴。
Man: Riders coming in!
男：骑手进来了！
- My little crow.
- I thought we'd lost you.
-我的小乌鸦。
-我以为我们失去你了。
Tormund: Almost.
Tormund:差不多。
Man: Put them in the stables.
男：把它们放在马厩里。
How did you find each other?
你们是怎么找到彼此的？
We met up at the last hearth.
我们在最后一个壁炉边见过面。
The dead got there first.
死者先到的。
The umbers?
棕色的吗?
Fighting for the night king now.
现在为夜王而战。
Tormund: We had to travel around them
to get here.
托蒙德：我们得绕着它们走
来这里。
Whoever's not here now
现在不在这里的人
is with them.
和他们在一起。
How long do we have?
我们还有多长时间？
Before the sun comes up tomorrow.
在明天太阳出来之前。
The big woman still here?
那个大女人还在这儿？
Jon: They're coming.
乔恩：他们来了。
Man: Next.
男:下一个。
Jon: We have dragonglass
and valyrian steel.
乔恩：我们有龙玻璃
还有瓦雷利亚钢。
Jon: But there are too many of them.
乔恩：但是他们人太多了。
Far too many.
太多了。
Our enemy doesn't tire.
我们的敌人不厌其烦。
Doesn't stop.
不停止。
Doesn't feel.
没有感觉。
We can't beat them
in a straight fight.
我们打败不了他们
在一场直接的战斗中。
Jaime: So, what can we do?
杰米：那我们该怎么办？
The night king made them all.
They follow his command.
都是夜王造的。
他们听从他的命令。
If he falls...
如果他摔倒了……
Getting to him
may be our best chance.
找到他
也许是我们最好的机会。
If that's true,
he'll never expose himself.
如果这是真的，
他永远不会暴露自己。
Bran: Yes, he will.
布兰：是的，他会的。
He'll come for me.
他会来接我的。
He's tried before, many times,
with many three-eyed ravens.
他以前试过很多次
有很多三眼乌鸦。
What does he want?
他想要什么？
An endless night.
一个无尽的夜晚。
He wants to erase this world,
and I am its memory.
他想毁灭这个世界
我是它的记忆。
Samwell:
Well, that's what death is, isn't it?
这就是死亡，不是吗？
Forgetting.
遗忘的时间。
Being forgotten.
被遗忘了。
If we forget where we've been
and what we've done,
如果我们忘了我们去过哪里
我们所做的，
we're not men anymore.
我们不再是男人了。
Just animals.
只是动物。
Your memories don't come from books.
你的记忆不是来自书本。
Your stories aren't just stories.
你的故事不仅仅是故事。
If I wanted to erase the world of men,
I'd start with you.
如果我想抹去男人的世界，
我想从你开始。
- How will he find you?
- His Mark is on me.
-他怎么找到你？
-他的印记在我身上。
He always knows where I am.
他总是知道我在哪里。
We'll put you in the crypt,
where it's safest.
我们会把你放进地下室，
最安全的地方。
Bran: No.
麸:没有。
We need to lure him into the open
before his army destroys us all.
我们得把他引出来
在他的军队消灭我们之前。
I'll wait for him in the godswood.
我会在神木林等他。
Sansa: You want us to use you as bait?
珊莎：你想让我们拿你当诱饵？
We're not leaving you alone
out there.
我们不会丢下你一个人的
在那里。
He won't be. I'll stay with him.
他不会的。我要陪着他。
With the ironborn.
和铁胎一起。
I took this castle from you.
我从你手里夺走了这座城堡。
Let me defend you now.
现在让我为你辩护。
We'll hold off the rest of them
for as long as we can.
我们要拖住其余的人
能待多久就待多久。
Tyrion: When the time comes,
ser davos and I will be on the walls,
提利昂：到时候，
戴佛斯爵士和我会守在城墙上，
to give you the signal
to light the trench.
给你信号
点亮战壕。
Ser davos is perfectly capable
of waving a torch on his own.
戴佛斯爵士完全有能力
独自挥舞着火炬。
You'll be in the crypt.
你会在地窖里。
Your grace, I have fought before,
I can do it again.
陛下，我以前打过仗，
我可以再来一次。
Alongside the men and women
risking their lives.
在男人和女人旁边
冒着生命危险。
There are thousands of them
and only one of you.
他们有成千上万个
而且只有一个人。
You can't fight as well as they can,
你打得不如他们好，
but you can think
better than any of them.
但是你可以这样想
比他们任何一个都好。
You're here because of your mind.
你在这里是因为你的思想。
If we survive, I'll need it.
如果我们能活下来，我需要它。
The dragons should give us
an edge in the field.
龙应该给我们
在这个领域的优势。
If they're in the field,
they're not protecting bran.
如果他们在现场，
他们没有保护麸皮。
We need to be near him.
我们得靠近他。
Not too near,
or the night king won't come.
不要太近，
否则夜王不会来。
But close enough to pursue him
when he does.
但要近到能追上他
当他知道的时候。
Dragonfire will stop him?
龙火会阻止他？
I don't know.
我不知道。
No one's ever tried.
没人试过。
We're all going to die.
我们都会死的。
But at least we die together.
但至少我们一起死。
Let's get some rest.
我们休息一下吧。
Your grace.
你的恩典。
Tyrion: Do you need help?
提利昂：你需要帮助吗？
You've had a strange journey.
你经历了一段奇怪的旅程。
Stranger than most.
比大多数人都奇怪。
I'd like to hear about it.
我想听听。
It's a long story.
说来话长。
If only we were trapped
in a castle...
要是我们被困住就好了
在城堡里……
In the middle of winter,
with nowhere to go.
在隆冬时节，
无处可去。
Missandei: Hello.
Missandei:你好。
Grey worm:
When Daenerys takes her throne...
灰虫:
当丹妮莉丝登上王位……
There will be no place for us here.
这里没有我们的容身之地。
I am onal to my queen.
我爱我的王后。
I will fight for her
until her enemies are defeated,
我会为她而战
直到她的敌人被打败
but when the war is over
and she has won...
但战争结束后
她赢了……
Do you want to grow old
in this place?
你想变老吗
在这个地方？
Is there nothing else you want to do,
你就没别的事想做了吗，
nothing else you want to see?
没有别的想看的了吗？
Naath.
Naath。
I'd like to see the beaches again.
我想再看看海滩。
Then I will take you there.
然后我带你去。
My people are peaceful.
我的人民爱好和平。
We cannot protect ourselves.
我们无法保护自己。
My people are not peaceful.
我的人民并不和平。
We will protect you.
我们会保护你的。
Have you told her yet?
你告诉她了吗？
Samwell: Mmm-hmm.
Samwell:唔。
Being careful.
小心。
Biding your time.
等待时机。
Waiting for the perfect...
等待完美的…
And now our watch begins.
现在我们开始计时。
Gilly? Little Sam?
侍从?小山姆?
They'll be safe down in the crypt.
他们在地下室里很安全。
If you want to join them...
如果你想加入他们…
To protect them.
为了保护他们。
Everyone seems to forget that I was
the first man to kill a white Walker.
大家似乎都忘了我是
第一个杀死异鬼的人
- I've killed thenns.
- Thenn.
-我杀过他们。
——Thenn。
I've saved gilly more than once.
我救过吉莉不止一次。
I stole a considerable number
of books from the citadel library,
我偷了不少钱
城堡图书馆的书，
survived the fist of the first men.
从先民的拳头中幸存下来。
You need me out there.
你需要我。
Well, if that's what it's come to,
we really are fucked.
好吧，如果事情到了这个地步
我们真的完蛋了。
Well, calling you "fucked"
wouldn't be strictly accurate.
叫你“操”
严格来说并不准确。
Samwell tarly.
Samwell焦油。
Slayer of white walkers.
异鬼杀手。
Lover of ladies.
女人的情人。
As if we needed any more signs
the world was ending.
好像我们还需要更多的提示似的
世界末日到了。
Think back to where we started.
回想一下我们开始的地方。
Us, grenn, pyp.
我们，葛兰，派普。
Now it's just us three.
现在就剩我们三个了。
Last man left, burn the rest of us.
最后一个人，把我们都烧死。
Tyrion: I wish father were here.
提利昂：我真希望父亲在这里。
I would love to see
the look on his face
我很想看看
他脸上的表情
when he realizes his two sons are
about to die defending winterfell.
当他意识到他的两个儿子
即将为保卫临冬城而死。
That would be something to see.
那将是值得一看的。
Tyrion: I remember the first time
we were here,
提利昂：我记得第一次
我们在这里，
the first time I saw this hall.
我第一次看到这个大厅的时候。
- Mmm.
- You were a golden lion.
——嗯。
-你是一只金狮。
I was a drunken whoremonger.
我是个醉醺醺的嫖客。
It was all so simple.
一切都那么简单。
It wasn't so simple.
事情没那么简单。
I was sleeping with my sister
and you had one friend in the world
我和我妹妹上床了
你在这世上只有一个朋友
who was sleeping with his sister.
和他妹妹上床的人。
I was speaking in relative terms.
我说的是相对而言的。
- Do you miss it?
- Of course I miss it.
-你想念它吗？
-我当然想了。
Well, my golden-lion days are done,
我的金狮生涯结束了，
but whoremongering
is still an option for you.
但嫖妓
仍然是你的选择。
It's not.
它不是。
Things would be easier if it were.
如果是这样，事情就容易多了。
The perils of self-betterment.
自我完善的危险。
Oh!
哦!
My lady.
我的夫人。
Brienne:
Oh, we didn't mean to interrupt.
一起:
哦，我们不是故意打扰你的。
We were just looking for
somewhere warm to...
我们只是在找
一个温暖的地方……
To contemplate your imminent death.
You've come to the right place.
思考你即将到来的死亡。
你来对地方了。
You want some of this piss?
It's not bad.
你想来点尿吗？
还不错。
- It's not good either.
- Thank you, my lord.
-也不好。
-谢谢你，大人。
I don't think that's wise.
我不认为这是明智的。
The battle might start at any moment.
战斗随时可能开始。
Half cup.
半杯。
- And you?
- Brienne: No, thank you.
-你呢？
不了，谢谢。
I should try and get some sleep.
我应该试着睡一会儿。
Jaime: You really think any of us
are going to sleep tonight?
詹姆：你真的认为我们中的任何一个
你今晚要睡觉吗？
Join us.
加入我们的行列。
All right.
好吧。
Just a bit.
只是一点点。
Davos: Well, what do we have here?
达沃斯：嗯，我们这里有什么？
Ser davos, join us.
戴佛斯爵士，加入我们。
No, none for me, thanks.
不，我不要，谢谢。
Came here for this.
我来这里就是为了这个。
I figured I could wait to die
freezing my balls off out there
我想我可以等死
我的蛋蛋都快冻掉了
or wait to die nice and warm in here.
或者等着暖和地死在这里。
It could be our last night
in this world, you know.
这可能是我们的最后一晚
在这个世界上，你知道。
Yes, well, I'm glad you're here.
是啊，我很高兴你来了。
Here fighting with us.
和我们一起战斗。
Glad you survived eastwatch.
很高兴你逃过了东望。
Would you like a drink?
你想喝点什么吗？
Brought my own.
我自己带了。
They call you "king killer."
他们叫你“国王杀手”。"
I'm sure someone does.
我肯定有人知道。
They call me "giantsbane."
他们叫我巨人。"
Want to know why?
想知道为什么吗？
I killed a giant when I was 10.
我十岁的时候杀了一个巨人。
Then I climbed right into bed
with his wife.
然后我爬上了床
和他的妻子。
When she woke up,
you know what she did?
当她醒来时，
你知道她做了什么吗？
Suckled me at her teat
for three months.
吮吸我的奶头
三个月。
Thought I was her baby.
我以为我是她的孩子。
That's how I got so strong.
这就是我变得如此强壮的原因。
Giant's milk.
巨人的牛奶。
Mmm.
嗯。
Maybe I will have that drink.
也许我该喝一杯。
You never used to shut up. Now you're
just sitting there like a mute.
你以前从来不闭嘴。现在你
就像个哑巴一样坐在那里。
Guess I've changed.
我想我变了。
What are you doing up here?
你在这里做什么？
What's it look like?
它看起来像什么？
No, I mean,
what are you doing up here?
不，我是说，
你在这里做什么？
You joined the brotherhood.
你加入了兄弟会。
You went beyond the wall with Jon.
You're here now. Why?
你和琼恩一起出了墙。
你现在在这里。为什么?
When was the last time
you fought for anyone but yourself?
上次是什么时候
你为别人而战，却不为自己？
I fought for you, didn't I?
我为你而战，不是吗？
Oh, for fuck's sake.
哦，看在上帝的份上。
May as well be at a bloody wedding.
就跟在婚礼上一样。
My lady.
我的夫人。
It's good to see you again.
很高兴再次见到你。
I'm sorry we parted the way we did.
很抱歉我们那样分手了。
Was he on your list?
他在你的名单上吗？
For a little while.
一段时间。
That's all right.
没关系。
The lord of light
has brought us together all the same.
光之王
还是让我们走到了一起。
This is his moment.
这是他的时刻。
- When light...
- Thoros isn't here anymore,
-当光…
-索罗斯不在了
so I hope you're not
about to give a sermon.
所以我希望你不是
马上要布道了。
Because if you are,
因为如果你是，
the lord of light's gonna wonder
why he brought you back 19 times
光之王会惊讶的
为什么他把你带回来19次
just to watch you die when
I Chuck you over this fucking wall.
就为了看着你死去
我把你扔过这堵墙。
Where are you going?
你要去哪里？
I'm not spending my final hours
with you two miserable old shits.
我不会把最后的时光浪费在这里
和你们两个可怜的老混蛋。
Hound: Hmm.
猎犬:嗯。
Arya: That for me?
艾莉亚：这是给我的？
This'll work.
这将工作。
Last time you saw me,
you wanted me to come to winterfell.
上次你见到我的时候
你要我来临冬城。
Mmm. Took the long road, but...
嗯。走了很长一段路，但是…
What did the red woman want with you?
那个红袍女人找你干什么？
She wanted my blood
for some kind of spell.
她想要我的血
为了某种咒语。
Why your blood?
为什么是你的血？
I'm Robert Baratheon's bastard.
我是劳勃·拜拉席恩的私生子。
I didn't know until she told me.
直到她告诉我我才知道。
She tied me up, stripped me down,
put leeches all over me.
她把我绑起来，扒光我的衣服，
让我浑身都是水蛭。
Was that your first time?
那是你的第一次吗？
No, yeah, I've never had leeches
put all over my cock.
不，我从来没吃过水蛭
涂在我的鸡巴上。
Your first time with a woman.
你第一次和女人在一起。
What?
怎么啦？
I... I didn't... iwasn't with her.
我…我没有……我没和她在一起。
Were you with other girls before that
在那之前你和其他女孩在一起吗
in king's landing?
在君临？
Or after?
还是之后?
You don't remember?
你不记得了？
- Yes, I was.
- One?
-是的，我是。
——一个吗?
Two?
两个?
- Twenty?
- Well, I didn't keep count.
- 20 ?
-我没数过
Yes, you did.
是的，你说了。
Three.
三。
We're probably going to die soon.
我们可能很快就要死了。
I want to know what it's like
before that happens.
我想知道那是什么感觉
在那之前。
Arya, I...
Arya,我…
I'm not the red woman.
我不是那个红衣女人。
Take your own bloody pants off.
把你自己的裤子脱了。
It's strange, isn't it?
很奇怪，不是吗？
Almost everyone here's fought
the starks
这里几乎每个人都打过仗
的斯塔克斯
at one time or another.
在某个时候。
And here we are in their castle,
ready to defend it.
现在我们在他们的城堡里，
准备好捍卫它。
Together.
在一起。
At least we'll die with honor.
至少我们会光荣地死去。
I think we might live.
我想我们能活下来。
I do.
我做的事情。
How many battles
have we survived between us?
有多少战斗？
我们还活着吗？
Ser davos seaworth.
戴佛斯·席渥斯爵士。
Survivor of both the Blackwater
and the battle of the bastards.
黑水河的幸存者
还有私生子之战。
All without a shred
of combat ability.
没有一丝一毫
战斗能力。
Tormund1mmm.
Tormund1mmm。
Ser Jaime Lannister,
fabled hero of the siege of pyke.
詹姆·兰尼斯特爵士，
传说中围攻派克城的英雄。
Fabled loser
of the battle of whispering wood.
传说中的失败者
低语森林之战。
Hear, hear!
听,听!
Ser brienne of tarth.
地球的布蕾妮爵士。
Defeated the hound in...
打败了猎犬……
Pardon me, lady brienne.
对不起，布蕾妮夫人。
Tormund: She's not a ser?
托蒙德：她不是爵士？
You're not a knight?
你不是骑士？
Women can't be knights.
女人不能成为骑士。
- Why not?
- Tradition.
-为什么？
——传统。
Fuck tradition.
操的传统。
I don't even want to be a knight.
我根本不想当骑士。
Tormund: I'm no king.
托蒙德：我不是国王。
But if I were,
但如果我是，
I'd knight you 10 times over.
我愿意给你十次封爵。
Jaime: You don't need a king.
詹姆：你不需要国王。
Any knight can make another knight.
任何骑士都可以制造另一个骑士。
I'll prove it.
我来证明。
Kneel, lady brienne.
跪下，布蕾妮夫人。
Jaime: Do you want to be
a knight or not?
詹姆：你想成为
是不是骑士？
Kneel.
跪。
In the name of the warrior,
以勇士之名，
I charge you to be brave.
我嘱咐你要勇敢。
In the name of the father,
以父亲的名义
I charge you to be just.
我要求你保持公正。
In the name of the mother,
以母亲的名义，
I charge you to defend the innocent.
我要求你保护无辜者。
Arise, brienne of tarth...
起来吧，地球的仙女……
A knight of the seven kingdoms.
七大王国的骑士。
Tyrion: Ser brienne of tarth!
提利昂：地球的布蕾妮爵士！
Knight of the seven kingdoms!
七大王国的骑士！
Jorah: We have all we need
to win this war.
乔拉：我们需要的都有了
赢得这场战争。
Lady mormont: I have trained my men,
women and children.
莫尔蒙夫人：我训练了我的手下，
妇女和儿童。
I have fought before.
I can fight again.
我以前打过仗。
我可以再次战斗。
Jorah: Please, listen to me.
You're the future of our house.
乔拉：拜托，听我说。
你是我们家的未来。
Lady mormont: I don't need you
to remind me of that.
莫尔蒙夫人：我不需要你
提醒我一下。
Jorah: You'll be safer in the crypt.
These things we're fighting...
乔拉：你在地窖里会更安全。
我们正在对抗的这些东西……
I will not hide underground.
我不会躲在地下。
I pledged to fight for the north,
and I will fight.
我发誓要为北境而战
我要战斗。
Man 1: I'm meant to relieve you.
You got it?
男1：我是来顶替你的。
明白了吗？
Man 2: Yeah, I got it.
男2：是的，我知道了。
Oh, I'm sorry, I didn't mean to...
哦，对不起，我不是故意的……
It's all right.
没关系的。
We're done here.
我们做完了。
I wish you good fortune, cousin.
祝你好运，表弟。
Thank you, my lady.
谢谢您，夫人。
- My lady.
- Soldier: My lady.
-夫人。
我的夫人。
What have you got there?
你拿的是什么？
It's called heartsbane.
这叫心毒。
It's my family sword.
这是我的家剑。
You still have a family.
你还有家人。
Yes. And I'd love
to defend them with it.
是。我很想
用它来保护他们。
But I can't really hold it upright.
但我拿不稳。
Your father,
he taught me how to be a man.
你的父亲,
他教我如何做人。
How to do what's right.
如何做正确的事。
This is right.
没错。
It's valyrian steel.
这是瓦雷利亚钢。
I'd be honored if you'd take it.
如果你接受，我会很荣幸。
I'll wield it in his memory...
我要用它来纪念他……
To guard the realms of men.
保卫人类的王国。
I'll see you when it's through.
办完后我去找你。
I hope we win.
我希望我们能赢。
- We'd better get some rest.
- No, let's stay a bit longer.
我们最好休息一下。
-不，我们再呆一会儿吧。
We're out of wine.
我们没有酒了。
How about a song?
唱首歌怎么样？
One of you must know one.
你们中一定有人认识。
- Ser davos?
- You'll pray for a quick death.
-戴佛斯爵士？
-你会祈祷快点死的
Tyrion: Ser brienne?
提利昂：布蕾妮爵士？
- Mmm-hmm.
- Hmm.
——嗯。
High in the halls
of the kings who are gone
在高高的大厅里
逝去的国王
Jenny would dance with her ghosts
珍妮会和她的鬼魂跳舞
the ones she had lost
and the ones she had found
她失去的那些
还有她找到的那些
and the ones
who had loved her the most
还有那些
谁最爱她
the ones who'd been gone
for so very long
那些已经离开的人
长久以来
she couldn't remember their names
她记不起他们的名字了
they spun her around
on the damp old stones
他们让她转了个圈
在潮湿的旧石头上
spun away all her sorrow and pain
驱散了她所有的悲伤和痛苦
and she never wanted to leave
她从未想过要离开
never wanted to leave
从未想过离开
Daenerys: Who's that?
丹妮莉丝：那是谁？
Lyanna stark.
Lyanna明显。
My brother rhaegar...
我哥哥雷加尔……
Everyone told me
he was decent and kind.
每个人都告诉我
他为人正派、善良。
He liked to sing.
他喜欢唱歌。
Gave money to poor children.
把钱给贫穷的孩子。
And he raped her.
然后他强奸了她。
Jon: He didn't.
乔恩：他没有。
He loved her.
他爱她。
They were married in secret.
他们秘密结婚了。
After rhaegar fell on the trident,
she had a son.
雷加尔倒在三叉戟上后
她有一个儿子。
Robert would have murdered the baby
if he ever found out,
罗伯特会杀了孩子的
如果他发现了
and lyanna knew it.
莱安娜知道这一点。
So the last thing she did...
所以她做的最后一件事…
As she bled to death
on her birthing bed
她失血过多而死
在她的产床上
was give the boy to her brother...
就是把孩子交给她哥哥
Ned stark...
Ned鲜明……
To raise as his bastard.
作为他的私生子抚养。
My name...
我的名字……
My real name...
我的真名……
Is aegon Targaryen.
是伊耿·坦格利安。
- That's impossible.
- I wish it were.
-不可能。
-我也希望是。
Who told you this?
谁告诉你的？
Bran.
麸皮。
- He saw it.
- He saw it?
-他看到了。
-他看到了？
And samwell confirmed it.
山姆威尔证实了这一点。
He read about their marriage
at the citadel
他读到了他们结婚的消息
在城堡里
without even knowing what it meant.
甚至不知道这是什么意思。
A secret no one in the world knew...
一个世界上无人知晓的秘密……
Except your brother
and your best friend.
除了你哥哥
还有你最好的朋友。
Doesn't seem strange to you?
你不觉得奇怪吗？
It's true, dany.
是真的，丹妮。
I know it is.
我知道。
If it were true,
如果这是真的，
it would make you the last male heir
of house Targaryen.
这会让你成为最后一个男性继承人
坦格利安家族的人
You'd have a claim to the iron throne.
你有资格继承铁王座。
Man: Form up!
男：列队！
Man: Get yourselves back!
男：快回去！
Woman: High in the halls
of the kings who are gone
女：高高在上
逝去的国王
Jenny would dance with her ghosts
珍妮会和她的鬼魂跳舞
the ones she had lost
她失去的那些
and the ones she had found
还有她找到的那些
and the ones
who had loved her the most
还有那些
谁最爱她
the ones who'd been gone
for so very long
那些已经离开的人
长久以来
she couldn't remember their names
她记不起他们的名字了
they spun her around
on the damp old stones
他们让她转了个圈
在潮湿的旧石头上
spun away all her sorrow and pain
驱散了她所有的悲伤和痛苦
and she never wanted to leave
她从未想过要离开
never wanted to leave
从未想过离开